# **MOHAMMED WASIF UDDIN**

#### **DETAILS**

PHONE

6827166147

**EMAIL** 

mwasifu@outlook.com

DATE OF BIRTH

10/04/1996

### LINKS

**LinkedIn** 

<u>Github</u>

Portfolio

#### SKILLS

React | Vue | Node.JS

Javascript | CSS | HTML

Bootstrap | JQuery

SQL

Java | C | C# | XAML-| C++ | Python | Ruby

#### LANGUAGES

English

• • • •

Bengali

• • • •

#### **PROFILE**

Recent Computer Science graduate with expertise in front end web development focusing on utilizing Javascript frameworks like React, Vue.JS and Node.JS with profiency in handling APIs (e.g. MailChimp, Postman), HTML, CSS, JavaScript and database management.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Junior Front-End Developer, MicroTech

Vienna, VA

Jul 2021 — Dec 2021

- Created and maintained new responsive React components utilizing third party JS libraries like JQuery, moment.js, Framer Motion, etc to be used through out the SPA.
- Improved the load time by 30% which increased customer screen time by 5 minutes.
- Used MailChimp API to add a subscription list to keep track of and follow customer engagement.
- Worked with a team of 3 to resolve front-end issues and collaborated using Git for version control.

### Software Developer, HM and RC

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Jan 2021 — Jun 2022

- Architected and developed a .NET 5 (Core) Windows database management application using WPF with XAML and C# following Material UI to shift from the legacy program.
- Maintained communication with the previous developer to resolve issues while using Git for version control.
- Introduced numerous upgrades over the last generation like generating custom reports, a todo list, etc increasing revenue by 37%.

#### EDUCATION

# BS Computer Science, The University of Texas at Dallas

Richardson

Jan 2016 — Dec 2020

- 1. Developed C chat app using TCP sockets for communication between server and client sides
- 2. Java parking lot simulator app focusing on binary trees for the backend
- 3. Pong game developed in Python
- 4. Weight conversion program developed in MIPS

## **PROJECTS**

## **Portfolio Website**

- React Single Page Application utilizing React Router
- · Use of React Hooks to handle states and user input

- Third party libraries like Tsparticle.JS to set up dynamic particles in the background and Tensorflow.js that uses machine learning to receive voice commands from the user
- Weather app that displays the current weather of the user's present location (uses OpenWeather API)
- · Bootstrap Integrated

## **Cryptocurrency Website**

- React website featuring ant design utilizes the use of React hooks such as useState and useEffect
- Uses CoinRankingAPI and BingNewsAPI through RapidAPI to provide realtime data and relevant news for each cryptocurrency
- · Uses Redux toolkit to create api and send query requests
- Uses chartjs to display detailed charts of the price distribution across a span of 5 years for each cryptocurrency

## **Blog Website**

- · Used Vuetify and Vue to develop a responsive UI
- · Register and Login capabilities
- · Extensive use of JavaScript, HTML and CSS
- · Worked with the backend team to fix bugs and deploy the blog on the www

### **DragonRuby Game**

- · Architected a Ruby top-down RPG game built on DragonRuby Game Toolkit
- · Collaborated with a team of 3 leading while in UI and level design
- Contributed new functions to the game toolkit's libraries improving hardware efficiency and load time